<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="stephan@lotk.de">Stephan Sann</author>
    <title>Glossary</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <!-- The body of the document contains a number of sections -->
    <section name="Glossary">
      <h4>Mailbox access protocols</h4>

      <p><a name="pop3">POP3</a>:
      <br/>
      Post Office Protocol Version 3 (RFC 1939). Supported by almost any mailbox
      server. Only one mailfolder ("INBOX") can be used.
      <br/>
      If you choose POP3 on the logon form, yawebmail will try to connect to
      port 110 (default TCP/IP port for POP3) on the demanded mailbox host.</p>

      <p><a name="imap">IMAP</a>:
      <br/>
      Internet Message Access Protocol (RFC 3501). Supported by many mailbox
      servers. IMAP supports the creation of multiple folders, in which you can
      organize your mails.      
      <br/>
      If you choose IMAP on the logon form, yawebmail will try to connect to
      port 143 (default TCP/IP port for IMAP) on the demanded mailbox host.</p>

      <p><a name="pop3s">POP3 (SSL) / POP3S</a>:
      <br/>
      Same as POP3, but all data will be transported over a SSL-Connection. Only
      a few servers support this protocol.
      <br/>
      If you choose POP3 (SSL) on the logon form, yawebmail will try to connect
      to port 995 (default TCP/IP port for POP3S) on the demanded mailbox host.
      </p>

      <p><a name="imaps">IMAP (SSL) / IMAPS</a>:
      <br/>
      Same as IMAP, but all data will be transported over a SSL-Connection. Only
      a few servers support this protocol.
      <br/>
      If you choose IMAP (SSL) on the logon form, yawebmail will try to connect
      to port 993 (default TCP/IP port for IMAPS) on the demanded mailbox host.
      </p>

      <h4>Sending mail</h4>

      <p><a name="smtp">SMTP</a>:
      <br/>
      Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (RFC 821 and RFC 2821). Supported by almost
      any mailserver. This protocol is used when you send an eMail via
      yawebmail. By default yawebmail suggests TCP/IP port 25 for
      SMTP-connections (you can change this value if necessary).</p>

      <p><a name="smtpAuth">SMTP Auth.</a>:
      <br/>
      SMTP with authentication. Same as SMTP, but the mailserver requires the
      user to authenticate himself with an username and a password.
      <br/>
      If you want to use SMTP Auth. with yawebmail, just fill in an username and
      a password on the "create new mail"-page.</p>

      <p><a name="smtpSsl">SMTP/SSL</a>:
      <br/>
      Same as SMTP, but all data will be transported over a SSL-Connection. The
      default TCP/IP port for SMTP/SSL is 465.</p>

      <p><a name="smtpTls">SMTP/TLS</a>:
      <br/>
      Same as SMTP, but all data will be transported over a TLS-Connection. The
      default TCP/IP port for SMTP/SSL is 587.</p>

      <h4>Misc</h4>

      <p><a name="idn">IDN</a>:
      <br/>
      Internationalized Domain Name - a domain name with non-ASCII-characters.
      If you send an eMail to a IDN-domain, yawebmail will automatically
      translate the recipients address to its Punycode-representation.</p>

      <p><a name="utf8">UTF-8</a>:
      <br/>
      8-bit Unicode Transformation Format. All eMail-texts will be encoded with
      UTF-8 by yawebmail. So the recipient should have no problem with special
      characters you use (of course his client must support UTF-8, too).</p>
    </section>
  </body>

</document>
