<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//Apache Software Foundation//DTD XDOC 1.0//EN"
        "http://maven.apache.org/dtd/xdoc_1_0.dtd" [

                <!ENTITY #8482 "&amp;#8482;">
        ]>

<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="stephan@lotk.de">Stephan Sann</author>
    <title>User-documentation: Logon</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <!-- The body of the document contains a number of sections -->
    <section name="Description">
      On this page you enter your login-data for your mailbox.
    </section>

    <section name="The GUI">
      <img src="images/screenshot_logon.jpg" width="780" height="600"/>
    </section>

    <section name="The input">
      <p>Language:
      <br/>
      If your local language is supported by yawebmail (and your browser is
      configured for this language), it should have been already selected.
      Otherwise select a language of you choice.</p>

      <p>Mailbox-Server:
      <br/>
      The server (host) where your Mailbox (POP3- or IMAP-Account) is located.
      If you don't know the hostname of your Mailbox please ask your
      eMail-account-provider.</p>

      <p>Mailbox-Protocol:
      <br/>
      Select if your eMail-account is accessible via
      <a href="glossary.html#pop3">POP3</a>,
      <a href="glossary.html#imap">IMAP</a>,
      <a href="glossary.html#pop3s">POP3/SSL</a> or
      <a href="glossary.html#imaps">IMAP/SSL</a> (some accounts support multiple
      protocols). If you're not sure, try POP3 first, then IMAP - or ask your
      eMail-account-provider.
      <br/>
      If you would like to log into a Google&#8482; Mail accout, try POP3 (SSL).
      </p>

      <p>Jaw-wrench-icon:
      <br/>
      Click the jaw-wrench-icon if you would like to specify a custom
      server-port to connect to (do this only if your eMail-account-provider
      told you so).</p>

      <p>Mailbox-Username:
      <br/>
      The username of your eMail-account. If you don't know the username of your
      Mailbox please ask your eMail-account-provider.</p>

      <p>Mailbox-Password:
      <br/>
      The password of your eMail-account. If you don't know the password of your
      Mailbox please ask your eMail-account-provider.</p>

      <p>Message-arrangement:
      <br/>
      This setting affects the arrangement of the message-listing(s).
      <br/>
      "All messages on one page" causes yawebmail to build one message-listing
      for all messages in a particular message-folder. This may result in a
      longer waiting period if you have a large amount of messages in your
      folder(s), since all message-headers have to be loaded.
      <br/>
      "Multiple pages (disables sorting)" causes yawebmail to split the content
      of your message-folder(s) to multiple message-listings (message 1 - 25,
      message 26 - 50, etc.). This feature disables an overall message-sorting
      since only the message-headers needed for a particular message-listing are
      loaded (and hence cannot be compared to the message-headers which are not
      loaded). The amount of messages per message-listing is defined by the
      yawebmail-admin (default: 25).
       </p>

      <p>"login"-button:
      <br/>
      Push the "login"-button to get access to your mailbox.</p>

      <p>"reset"-button:
      <br/>
      Push the "reset"-button to reset all input-fields.</p>

      <p>"help"-button:
      <br/>
      Push the "help"-button to get help for this screen. Actually you will see
      this page ;-)</p>
    </section>

  </body>

</document>
