<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="stephan@lotk.de">Stephan Sann</author>
    <title>User-documentation: Create new mail</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <!-- The body of the document contains a number of sections -->
    <section name="Description">
      On this page you can create a new message.
    </section>

    <section name="The GUI">
      <img src="images/screenshot_new_mail.jpg" width="780" height="600"/>
      <br/><br/><br/>

      Depending on how the administrator configured yawebmail, there are
      three possible appearances:
      <br/><br/>

      <a name="config1">Configuration 1</a>:
      <br/>
      <img src="images/smtpHostChoice_free.gif" width="440" height="51"/>
      <br/>
      (free choice of SMTP-host)
      <br/><br/>

      <a name="config2">Configuration 2</a>:
      <br/>
      <img src="images/smtpHostChoice_domain.gif" width="440" height="51"/>
      <br/>
      (free choice of SMTP-host within the domain of the mailbox-server)
      <br/><br/>

      <a name="config3">Configuration 3</a>:
      <br/>
      <img src="images/smtpHostChoice_none.gif" width="440" height="51"/>
      <br/>
      (no choice of SMTP-host (host set by administrator))
    </section>

    <section name="The input">
      <p>SmtpServer / Port (not available in <a href="#config3">configuration
      3</a>):
      <br/>
      Fill in the hostname and port of the SMTP-server which shall be used to
      process the transport of the message. In <a href="#config2">configuration
      2</a> you are limited to chose the SMTP-subdomain-prefix (optional), the
      domain will be taken from your mailbox-login. If you don't know the
      hostname and/or port of your SMTP-server please ask your
      eMail-account-provider.
      </p>

      <p>Auth: User / Pass:
      <br/>
      Just in case you SMTP-server needs authorisation, fill in your username
      and password. Otherwise leave blank. If you're not sure try to omit this
      input first. In case this doesn't work for you, ask your
      eMail-account-provider.</p>

      <p>"SSL"-Checkbox:
      <br/>
      Activate this checkbox if you want to send your mail over a
      SSL-connection. This must be supported by the according SMTP-Server (if
      you're not sure about this, ask your eMail-account-provider). The default
      TCP-IP port for SMTP-SSL-connections is 465.</p>

      <p>"TLS"-Checkbox:
      <br/>
      Activate this checkbox if you want to send your mail over a
      TLS-connection. This must be supported by the according SMTP-Server (if
      you're not sure about this, ask your eMail-account-provider). The default
      TCP-IP port for SMTP-TLS-connections is 587.</p>

      <p>From:
      <br/>
      Fill in your own eMail-Address. Be aware that some SMTP-servers will check
      if the given eMail-Address matches to the used SMTP-Auth-user (if used).
      Furthermore keep an eye on typing errors. If your SMTP-server doesn't
      check the from-address, you will get no response-mails if you got a typo
      in this.</p>

      <p>To:
      <br/>
      Fill in the eMail-Address of the recipient. Separate multiple recipients
      with commas.</p>

      <p>CC:
      <br/>
      Fill in the eMail-Address of the carbon-copy-recipient. Separate multiple
      carbon-copy-recipients with commas.</p>

      <p>BCC:
      <br/>
      Fill in the eMail-Address of the blind-carbon-copy-recipient. Separate
      multiple blind-carbon-copy-recipients with commas.</p>

      <p>Subject:
      <br/>
      Fill in the subject of the eMail.</p>

      <p>File-attachments:
      <br/>
      If you would like to attach files to the eMail, you got to browse your
      local file-system for the file and click "upload file" to transfer the
      file to yawebmail for each attachment.</p>

      <p>eMail-Text:
      <br/>
      Fill in the message-content in plain text.</p>

      <p>"send mail"-button:
      <br/>
      Push the "send mail"-button to send the mail. You will be forwarded to the
      "Mailfolder overview"-page.</p>

      <p>"reset"-button:
      <br/>
      Push the "reset"-button to delete all message-related inputs and start
      over again.</p>

      <p>"cancel"-button:
      <br/>
      Push the "cancel"-button to quit message-creation and return to the
      "Mailfolder overview"-page.</p>

      <p>"help"-button:
      <br/>
      Push the "help"-button to get help for this screen. Actually you will see
      this page ;-)</p>

      <p>"logout"-button:
      <br/>
      Push the "logout"-button to log out from the current session.
      All informations collected during the session will be discarded.</p>
    </section>
  </body>

</document>
