<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="stephan@lotk.de">Stephan Sann</author>
    <title>User-documentation: Mailfolder overview</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <!-- The body of the document contains a number of sections -->
    <section name="Description">
      On this page you see the current messages existing in the current
      mailfolder. With POP3 there's only one folder ("INBOX"), so
      folder-navigation is deactivated. With IMAP you can create different
      mailfolders - a folder-navigation will appear on the left-hand side.
    </section>

    <section name="The GUI">
      <img src="images/screenshot_overview.jpg" width="780" height="600"/>
    </section>

    <section name="The input">
      <p>"delete selected mails"-button:
      <br/>
      Push the "delete selected mails"-button to delete the selected mails (to
      select a particular mail mark the corresponding preceding checkbox).</p>

      <p>"check for new mails"-button:
      <br/>
      Push the "check for new mails"-button to check for new mails on your
      mailbox-server. The mailfolder overview will be refreshed.</p>

      <p>"create new mail"-button:
      <br/>
      Push the "create new mail"-button to get to the "create new mail"-page.
      Check the "create new mail"-documentation to get further informations.</p>

      <p>"help"-button:
      <br/>
      Push the "help"-button to get help for this screen. Actually you will see
      this page ;-)</p>

      <p>"logout"-button:
      <br/>
      Push the "logout"-button to log out from the current session.
      All informations collected during the session will be discarded.</p>

      <p>"create folder"-button (not available with POP3-protocol):
      <br/>
      Push the "create folder"-button to create a new subfolder within the
      current folder. The name for the new folder has to be supplied in the
      textfield above this button. If this button is grey, the mailbox server
      doesn't allow the creation of subfolders within the current folder.</p>

      <p>"delete folder"-button (not available with POP3-protocol):
      <br/>
      Push the "delete folder"-button to delete the subfolder selected in the
      dropdownlist above this button. If this button is grey, the mailbox server
      doesn't allow subfolders within the current folder.</p>

      <p>Subject-links:
      <br/>
      Each message-subject is equipped with a link to the corresponding "View
      single message"-page. There you can read the chosen message. Check the
      "View single message"-documentation to get further informations.</p>

      <p>Column-header:
      <br/>
      You can change the sort-order of the displayed mails by clicking on the
      appropriate column-header.</p>

      <p>"Spamlevel"-column:
      <br/>
      If you got Spamassassin (http://spamassassin.apache.org/) installed on
      your mailserver, it will add a "X-Spam-Level"-header to each eMail you
      get. It displays the email's total spam-score using the asterisk character
      (*). For further informations check the Spamassassin-Website. If the
      "X-Spam-Level"-header is not found in a message, the string "[not set]"
      will be displayed in this column.</p>

      <p>"select all"-button:
      <br/>
      Push the "select all"-button to select all mails (all preceding checkboxes
      will be marked).</p>

      <p>"move selected messages to" (not available with POP3-protocol):
      <br/>
      Here you can move selected messages to other folders. Select the desired
      target-folder and click the "execute"-button.</p>
    </section>

  </body>

</document>
